<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><metadata>
    <idinfo>
        <citation>
            <citeinfo>
                <title>Soils (MU) - State of Hawaii</title>
                <onlink>https://geodata.hawaii.gov/arcgis/rest/services/Terrestrial/MapServer/42</onlink>
                <onlink>https://files.hawaii.gov/dbedt/op/gis/data/soils.pdf</onlink>
            </citeinfo>
        </citation>
        <descript>
            <abstract>[Metadata] This dataset (MU) is called the Gridded SSURGO (gSSURGO) Database and is derived from the Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) Database. Source:  U.S. Department of Agriculture, Natural Resources Conservation Service.For more information, please see metadata at: https://files.hawaii.gov/dbedt/op/gis/data/soils.pdfNote:	 Downloaded from https://datagateway.nrcs.usda.gov, 2016For additional tables and more information, visit the following pages:https://websoilsurvey.sc.egov.usda.gov/App/WebSoilSurvey.aspx (choose Download Soils Data tab, State = Hawaii - from here, you can download all shapefiles and tabular data for each county).Tables and columns metadata:https://www.nrcs.usda.gov/wps/portal/nrcs/detail/national/soils/?cid=nrcs142p2_053631For additional information, please contact the Hawaii Statewide GIS Program at gis@hawaii.gov.</abstract>
            <purpose>This dataset (MU) is called the Gridded SSURGO (gSSURGO) Database and is derived from the Soil Survey Geographic (SSURGO) Database.</purpose>
        </descript>
        <keywords>
            <theme>
                <themekt>None</themekt>
                <themekey>Terrestrial</themekey>
                <themekey>HawaiiStateGIS</themekey>
                <themekey>State of Hawaii</themekey>
                <themekey>Kauai</themekey>
                <themekey>Oahu</themekey>
                <themekey>Molokai</themekey>
                <themekey>Lanai</themekey>
                <themekey>Kahoolawe</themekey>
                <themekey>Maui</themekey>
                <themekey>Hawaii</themekey>
                <themekey>Soils</themekey>
                <themekey>SSURGO</themekey>
                <themekey>gSSURGO</themekey>
                <themekey>Gridded SSURGO</themekey>
                <themekey>Soil Survey Geographic Database</themekey>
                <themekey>NRCS</themekey>
            </theme>
        </keywords>
        <accconst>None</accconst>
        <useconst>State of Hawaii Terms of UseThe
 contents of this web page are public domain and to the extent indicated
 otherwise in the Terms of Use, are exempt from Terms of Use policy 
restrictions. There are no expressed warranties associated with the 
release of this data or product. Specifically, no warranty is made that 
the GIS data or any subsequent updates will be error free and no 
warranty is made regarding the positional or thematic accuracy of the 
GIS data. The GIS data and any features depicted do not represent or 
confer any legal rights, privileges, benefits, boundaries or claims of 
any kind. The Office of Planning and Sustainable Development encourages 
users to report any discrepancies or errors found.  Contact:   Hawaii 
Statewide GIS Program, Office of Planning and Sustainable Development, 
State of Hawaii; PO Box 2359, Honolulu, Hi. 96804; (808) 587-2846; 
email: gis@hawaii.gov; Website:  https://planning.hawaii.gov/gis.</useconst>
        <datacred>HawaiiStateGIS, Hawaii Statewide GIS Program, USDA NRCS</datacred>
    </idinfo>
    <metainfo>
        <metd>20201031</metd>
        <metc>
            <cntinfo>
                <!--no contact person or organization name available-->
            </cntinfo>
        </metc>
        <metstdn>FGDC Content Standard for Digital Geospatial Metadata</metstdn>
        <metstdv>FGDC-STD-001-1998</metstdv>
        <mettc>local time</mettc>
    </metainfo>
</metadata>
